metamarkets.com 2013-03-28

# Privacy Policy | Metamarkets

## METAMARKETS GROUP, INC.

## PRIVACY POLICY

Last Updated: August 26, 2011

Welcome to our Web site, www.metamarkets.com (the “Site”), owned by Metamarkets Group, Inc. (“Metamarkets,” “we,” or “us”). This privacy policy describes what information we collect from users of our Site, other than through the “Client Login” portal, and how we use such information. By using our Site, you consent to the data collection and use practices described below. Please be aware that this Privacy Policy and the choices you make on this Site will not necessarily apply to personal information you may have provided to Metamarkets in the context of other, separately operated, Metamarkets products or services, including the “Client Login” portal on the Site.

## Personal Information

“Personal information,” as used in this privacy policy, is information that specifically identifies an individual, such as an individual’s name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address. Personal information also includes information about an individual’s activities, such as information about his or her activity on the Site, and demographic information, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area, and preferences, when any of this information is linked to personal information that identifies that individual.

Personal information does not include “aggregate” or other non-personally identifiable information. Aggregate information is information that we collect about a group or category of products, services, or users that is not personally identifiable or from which individual identities are removed. We may use and disclose aggregate information, and other non-personally identifiable information, for various purposes.

## Collection of Information

## Passive Information Collection

When you visit the Site, some information is automatically collected, such as your IP address, browser type, system type, the content and pages that you access on the Site, “referring URL” (i.e., the page from which you navigated to the Site), the pages you navigate to on the Site, and from which you leave the Site, as well as the time you spend on the Site.

We collect this information passively using technologies such as standard server logs, cookies, and clear GIFs (also known as “Web beacons”). We use passively-collected information to administer, operate, and improve the Site and our other services and systems, and to provide services and content that are tailored to you. If we link or associate any information gathered through passive means with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information under this policy. Otherwise, we use information collected by passive means in non-personally identifiable form only.

Also, please be aware that third parties may set cookies on your hard drive or use other means of passively collecting information about your use of their services or content. We do not have access to, or control over, these third-party means of passive data collection.

## Collection of Voluntarily Provided Information

We collect personal information that our users provide to us in a variety of ways on the Site. For instance, when you request information about our services or otherwise communicate with us, we collect the personal information that you provide to us. We may collect personal information such as name, e-mail address, city, state, country, other demographic information, and your interests and preferences in these manners.

## Information from Other Sources

We may receive information about you, including personal information, from third parties, and may combine this information with other personal information we maintain about you. If we do so, this policy governs any combined information that we maintain in personally identifiable format.

## Use of Personal Information

We use personal information to provide services and information that you request; to enhance, improve, operate, and maintain the Site and services; to prevent fraudulent use of our Site and services; to tailor your user experience; to maintain a record of our dealings with you, and for other administrative purposes.

We may also use personal information you provide to contact you regarding our products, services, and offers that we believe you may find of interest. If you receive commercial email from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the email. You also may opt-out from receiving marketing communications from us by sending your request to us by email at info@metamarkets.com or by postal mail at the mailing address given at the end of this policy.

## Disclosure of Personal Information

We are not in the business of selling personal information about our users to third parties. We may disclose personal information to third-party service providers (e.g., payment processing and data storage and processing facilities) that assist us in our work. We limit the personal information provided to these service providers to that which is reasonably necessary for them to perform their functions.

We may also disclose personal information if we believe that doing so is legally required or is in our interest to protect our property or other legal rights (including, but not limited to, enforcement of our agreements), or the rights or property of others.

Personal information that you include in a comment to our blog on the Site, or in any other information you post to public areas of the Site (each, a “Submission”) will be publicly available and may be used by us or by other third parties without restriction. You include personal information in any Submissions at your sole risk. Even if a Submission is removed from the Site, caching and archiving services may have saved the Submission, and other users or third parties may have copied or stored it.

In addition, information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of company assets, or similar transaction, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which personal information could be transferred to third parties as one of our business assets.

## Links

For your convenience, the Site may contain links to other Web sites, products, or services that we do not own or operate. If you choose to visit or use any third-party products or services, please be aware that this policy will not apply to your activities or any information you disclose while using third-party products or services or otherwise interacting with third parties.

## Children

Children’s safety is important to us, and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active interest in the online activities of their children. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 without obtaining parental consent.

## International Visitors

Our Site is hosted in the United States and is generally intended for the United States visitors. If you visit from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please be aware that you are transferring personal information to the United States. The United States does not have the same data protection laws as the EU and some other regions. By providing personal information to us, you consent to the transfer of it to the United States and the use of it in accordance with this policy.

## Security

We use reasonable security measures that are designed to protect personal information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. Please note, however, that no data security measures can be guaranteed to be completely effective. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any personal information or other information. You transmit personal information to us at your own risk.

## Updates to This Policy

We may occasionally update this policy. When we do, we will also revise the “last updated” date at the beginning of the policy. Your continued use of this Site after such changes will be subject to the then-current policy. We encourage you to periodically review this policy to stay informed about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information.

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this privacy policy, please contact us using the following contact information:

Metamarkets Group Inc.  
625 2nd Street, Suite #230  
San Francisco, CA 94107
